<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-12-04T18:21:14+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sharpscription - a blog by Joe Sharp</title><subtitle>Joe Sharp a fullstack developer with expertise in Ruby, SublimeText, Unix/Linux and a variety of knowledge on other technologies &amp; programming languages.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Converting my main site to Jekyll</title><link href="/posts/converting-my-main-site-to-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Converting my main site to Jekyll" /><published>2020-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/posts/converting-my-main-site-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="/posts/converting-my-main-site-to-jekyll/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After the success with the blog&lt;/strong&gt; I decided to see how much trouble it would be to convert my main website to Jekyll. After all it is not a full blown web application or anything. I have started to really like being able to keep my content away from all the scaffolding in the HTML. Markdown is something I use quite frequently anyway. I use it in Jira/Confluence, GitHub, and Slack. I have even grown a bit attached to formatting my PRs at work in a aesthetically pleasing way. If it wasn’t enough that it is easy enough for me to use that I will actually update this blog, it certainly has a few other advantages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;go-big-or-go-home&quot;&gt;Go big or go home&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started out small with the tests from before. This time I decided the best way to get really comfortable with Jekyll was to just jump right in. I opened a new branch on my personal site’s repository and followed a guide that the Jekyll website had to offer: &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/tutorials/convert-site-to-jekyll/&quot;&gt;https://jekyllrb.com/tutorials/convert-site-to-jekyll/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the article made the conversion a piece of cake. I spent a little time sorting through a silly YAML mistake but other than that it was smooth sailing to convert all of my site content to Markdown and the HTML scaffolding into HTML templates to include where needed. My Rubyist mind was delighted that I could easily use loops to simplify some of the templates. I can’t wait to try more of the features I now have at my fingertips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will probably try to make it through some of the minor style issues and other bugs while I learn some more about Jekyll and try using it to generate some other websites. I have created sites for family members in the past, so maybe it is time I make a way for them to be able to update their own content without needing to know HTML. 🤔&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mad kudos goes out to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/team/&quot;&gt;Core Team&lt;/a&gt; at Jekyll. It’s been a while since I have been this excited about a tool or technology. If you want to get started with Jekyll yourself take a look here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/&quot;&gt;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I have created sites for family members in the past so maybe it is time I make a way for them to be able to update their own content without needing to know HTML. 🤔</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Updating my blog with only a browser</title><link href="/posts/updating-my-blog-with-only-a-browser/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Updating my blog with only a browser" /><published>2020-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/posts/updating-my-blog-with-only-a-browser</id><content type="html" xml:base="/posts/updating-my-blog-with-only-a-browser/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time to put Jekyll to the test!&lt;/strong&gt; If this is really as easy as I hoped, I should be able to update my blog with only a web browser. I should even be able to update it from a phone if I really needed to. For this test, I plan to open a new branch directly from GitHub’s online text editor. Once the branch has been opened from the text in this post, I would then hopefully be able to add an additional file directly from the web browser which could be a screenshot of this screen. Getting a screenshot from say another computer should be trivial, but also uploading a picture directly from a phone would likely be possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lets-start-small&quot;&gt;Let’s start small&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I will limit the test to just those two items. New text, and a new picture to go with it. So once the new branch has the media I can open a pull request. If I have the opportunity to preview the post it would be preferred but is not required. If you use GitHub frequently, you might know there is a Preview option I can use that will show me roughly how the markdown will style the post. The biggest question is will GitHub and Jekyll process the new post markdown and turn it into HTML. If it can’t we will fail this test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-did-it-work&quot;&gt;So did it work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess we will find out here in just a moment. I plan to do a follow-up to the post or simply edit this last paragraph with the results. If I am able to do an in-place edit from the browser as well, it has earned some extra credit in my book. I am pretty optimistic that all of this should work. I mean would someone on the Internet really lie like that? Right to my face?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: Well it definitely did not “just work” but not all is lost. I configured a GitHub action that should process this for me. Let’s see how it goes. …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 2: Wow, it works amazingly well! I followed an extremely simple guide on configuring a GitHub action along with a repository secret. Now when I commit changes to my main branch, GitHub spins up a Docker instance and converts my markdown using Jekyll. The site changes are made available almost immediately. It works so well I am finalizing my update here from my phone!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The site changes are made available almost immediately. It works so well I am finalizing my update here from my phone!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Using Jekyll for creating a personal blog</title><link href="/posts/using-jekyll-for-creating-a-personal-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using Jekyll for creating a personal blog" /><published>2020-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/posts/using-jekyll-for-creating-a-personal-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="/posts/using-jekyll-for-creating-a-personal-blog/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blogging is too much work,&lt;/strong&gt; so why have I decided to even try it again? It takes a long time to get a website up and running and get the layout just right and by the time I have finished I don’t ever want to touch it again. I don’t have much luck with ever updating a website again once I have it the way I like it. In the past I have had blog sections to my web pages, it always required having to go and boot up my feature-bloated IDE or WYSIWYG editor, and honestly, after a post or two it was over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-if-i-could-just-write-a-program&quot;&gt;What if I could just write a program…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often times would dream of writing a program that would take little bits of my text and spin up full web pages. I would dream of being able to update the blog from anywhere without even needing a proper text editor. I don’t particularly want to join sites that allow this because then I give up my style, and honestly a whole lot more if you have been paying attention to the real costs of social media. I don’t want people to have ads shoved down their throat just to see what I am up to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, before I undertook the task of finally writing something, I wanted to see what was out there. No sense rewriting the wheel. I heard about GitHub pages and thought it might be worth trying out. I am used to being able to push code from any computer, and I know they also have online editors, so I figured I would check it out. That is when I got introduced to Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-it-does-for-me&quot;&gt;What it does for me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Jekyll I can create short little markdown files that then get pushed to my GitHub repository. From there the magic happens. Jekyll builds and deploys my site within my repository and GitHub Pages picks up the changes. The new blog post is instantly available on the web. It took me less time to set up and configure Jekyll and GitHub Pages than it previously would have taken me to publish a single blog post. I’m sold!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I often times would dream of writing a program that would take little bits of my text and spin up full web pages. I would dream of being able to update the blog from anywhere without needing even a proper text editor.</summary></entry></feed>